

15 Stanton St, Unit 1B

(646) 924-7718

@ me@joeblack.nyc

in joeblack949

joeblackwaslike

Summary_

Passionate engineer and linux expert with 7 years of experience seeking a backend engineering role where my expertise in python will help drive the success of a team and product that I genuinely believe in. I'm energetic, self-managed, determined, embody the principles of grit.

Skills

Hard Skills Python (1), Bash (5), Javascript (5), GraphQL (5), Cypher (5), Solidity (5), Golang (5), Ruby/Rails (5), Django (5), Flask (5)

Soft Skills Public Speaking (2), Negotiation (4), Humor (5), Intuition (5)

Languages Greek (Native), English (Fluent)

Work Experience _____

Senior Python Engineer 08/2019 - 03/2020

Code & Theory New York, NY

Brought in to work on the CNN Datacloud, which powers John King's Magic Wall, a multi-touch interface for displaying real-time and historical election results and various data of a geospatial nature that changes over time, as well as the CNN election center website.

Senior Software Engineer 04/2019 - 08/2019

See-Thru Healthcare

Brooklyn, NY See-Thru Healthcare was a small (5 person, 2 dev), seed-funded, health-tech startup whose main product was a transparent

marketplace with a multi-faceted search engine for discovering and booking appointments with behavior-health telemedicine providers.

Co-founder & Senior Software Engineer

06/2017 - 12/2018

New York, NY

Co-founded a Pre-ICO start-up to research, fund, and develop a privacy-focused, decentralized communications and messaging app similar to Signal but unblockable by firewalls and not reliant on centralized hosting infrastructure and governance.

Education ____

M.Sc. Computer Science

01/2014 - 01/2017

Ivy Tech College Indianapolis, IN

B.Sc. Computer Science

01/2012 - 01/2014

Ivy Tech College Indianapolis, IN

Graduated second in class, had courses in computer architecture, algorithms, software engineering, database systems, linear algebra

Extracurricular Activities

Mentor 2013 - 2015

Noisebridge Hackerspace

Speaker 2014

HackMiami Conference

Delivered a bio-hacking talk discussing the usage of various technologies, proteins, and growth factors for cognitive enhancement.

Projects_

BTCPay-python longer for testing purposes

01/2012 - 01/2014

A pythonic, object-oriented interface to performing cryptography operations and key management using Gnu Privacy Guard (GPG).

GPGKeyring 01/2012 - 01/2014